<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PAAW</title>
    <description>The Performance Adaptive Aeroelastic Wing program. Yes, it's a morphing wing!
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 13:39:46 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 13:39:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Status</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planning on holding monthy technical meetings with NASA researchers. Notionally these will be the last Thursday of every month at 2 PM Central Time, need to check on availability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;status-update&quot;&gt;Status Update&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maewing1&quot;&gt;mAEWing1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CM Soft converted FEM model, good matching with VT FEM model&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FEM model surfaces are deployable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Current FEM is best and final prior to updating with experimental data from mass properties and GVT testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next steps:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Compute flutter speeds&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Create Reduced Order Models for control law design (MIDAAS and UMN LPV)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dave S. Flight Dynamics Model has preliminary flutter speeds
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sensitive to Cmq
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Important to BFF, investigating the relationship&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Longitudinal dynamics only&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Will have linear models in about 1 week&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VT has a preliminary flutter analysis complete
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Will update using Zaero&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;STI is collecting abstracts for a special session planned at SciTech on PAAW&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;STI has a preliminary draft for the ASE model survey
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Inlcudes descriptions of modeling approaches used sorted by aircraft&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UMN will update to include more general descriptions of modeling approaches&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mAEWing1 center body construction complete, systems integration in work
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Anticipating a mid May completion of the first mAEWing1 aircraft&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/04/30/status.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/04/30/status.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>status</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Status</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recap of Aerospace Flutter and Dynamics Council meeting from Dave S.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;status-update&quot;&gt;Status Update&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maewing1&quot;&gt;mAEWing1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VT updated FEM to include:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Spring elements for control surfaces&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Point mass locations for flaps&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Accelerometer locations&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CM Soft received updated FEM and is in process of converting for their use in CFD / CSD model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maewing2&quot;&gt;mAEWing2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VT updated shape optimization algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/04/23/status.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/04/23/status.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>status</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Status</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;status-update&quot;&gt;Status Update&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;STI started ASE model survey document&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invited session at Science and Technology Forum next year focused on PAAW&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maewing1-modeling&quot;&gt;mAEWing1 modeling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CFD / CSD model
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;CFD and FEM models complete&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;CM Soft converting format and adding control surfaces&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should have CFD / CSD model in the next couple weeks&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduced Order Models
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Determine number of modes
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Probably the first 6 modes in each axis&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Within bandwidth of actuators (10 - 14 Hz) and slightly above&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Velocity range 20 - 60 knots in 10 knot increments&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Should be complete in the next 3 - 4 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FEM Update
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;mAEWing1 WS1 build, static, and dynamic testing complete&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Can update mass properties in model&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Future FEM models should include:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Elements for control surfaces&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nodes at the sensor locations&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maewing2&quot;&gt;mAEWing2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VT wing shape optimization progress, will get an update next week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/04/09/status.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/04/09/status.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>status</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tactical Meeting, UMN and Aurora</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aurora has contacts with foam core suppliers that can meet mAEWing1 tolerances, will contact them to discuss supplying future center body and wing foam cores&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mAEWing2 mold construction will be lead through Aurora, either in-house or through subcontracts
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UMN will post preliminary mAEWing2 OML&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Need to define mAEWing2 material and manufacturing process, whether autoclave or heat application is needed will affect tooling material choices&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;mAEWing2 tooling will need integration guides&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aurora will begin working with NASA AFRC on xAEWing3 airworthiness requirements, procedures, and documentation
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UMN will work to find the NASA flight approval process&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aurora will begin working on a manufacturing plan for xAEWing3, including determining design review milestone dates needed to have a completed wing ready in time to meet program milestones.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Likely will include a concept design review, preliminary design review, and critical/manufacturing design review&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Need to determine whether we use hard or soft tooling. Soft tooling will work for the program, but hard tooling may be desired by NASA for future research.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tactical/2015/04/03/tactical.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tactical/2015/04/03/tactical.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tactical</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Status</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The updated center body, being built and integrated for the mAEWing1 flight testing, will be named Sköll. As a reminder the previous center body that was used for systems and operational development work, and is being used for some rigid flight testing, is called Fenrir.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will start referring to the wings by wing type and a wing set number. So the current set of wings being integrated is mAEWing1 Wing Set 1 or mAEWing1 WS1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;status-updates&quot;&gt;Status Updates&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maewing-1&quot;&gt;mAEWing 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mAEWing1 design v2.3 has been released. This should be considered the build to configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mAEWing1 WS 1 is nearing completion:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Actuators and linkages have been installed&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wiring and accelerometer installation is nearing completion (expected completion date 20150407)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mAEWing1 WS 1 testing:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Static testing complete&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dynamic testing expected to be complete by 20150410&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Freeplay test complete
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Found less than about 0.25 degrees of freeplay. The linkage and hinge have no freeplay, all of the freeplay is in the actuator. This test was rudimentary, but the freeplay is low enough that we’re not planning further testing unless simulation and analysis show that we need more accurate information.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foam delivered from a supplier for Sköll center body was very out of spec, should receive updated parts from our supplier week of April 6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overall, we’re running 1 - 2 weeks behind schedule for mAEWing1 build and test; instead of an April 20th completion date, we’re now projecting early May.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FEM complete for mAEWing1, will update with GVT data when it becomes available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CFD complete for mAEWing1, will begin work on CFD/CSD model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maewing2&quot;&gt;mAEWing2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MDAO approach and research plan for mAEWing2 complete.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preliminary CFD for mAEWing2 complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/04/02/status.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/04/02/status.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>status</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Status</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UMN to measure mAEWing1 actuator freeplay&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will likely leave mAEWing1 stiff for initial flights to gather aerodynamic data, then cut skin and foam to be flexible for flutter suppression and shape modification&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dave S sent a working paper on preliminary aerodynamic results. Need to estimate pitching moment from the body flaps during flight tests; this control surface is a large contributor to flutter suppression, but has very low pitching moment effectiveness (primarily contributes lift force)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Further analysis of Fenrir flight indicates that increasing the rigid body pitch damper gain could have excited the center-body flexibility. Updates to the aircraft design for mAEWing1 should remove this flexibility.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VT finished the mAEWing1 FEM model and will be verifying the model with UMN. VT also conducted some preliminary aero modeling for mAEWing1, which is being used to develop MDAO tools for the mAEWing2 design.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The mAEWing1 FEM model will be updated following Ground Vibration Testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/03/26/status.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/03/26/status.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>status</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Status</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dates / times that work for the mAEWing1 design review, given in central time, are:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Thursday, February 26: 12 PM&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Friday, February 27: 10 AM, 1 PM, 3 PM, 4 PM&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll hear from NASA which works best for them, likely the Thursday time slot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;status-updates&quot;&gt;Status Updates&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;year-1-modeling-tasks&quot;&gt;Year 1 Modeling Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;survey-of-modeling-approaches&quot;&gt;Survey of Modeling Approaches&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;End goal of PAAW is a validated tool chain that designers can use for flexible / morphing vehicles, modeling is an important aspect of this toolchain
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Survey modeling approaches, assumptions, and implications&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start with exploring modeling approaches used for current and past ASE aircraft programs (narrow scope)
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;STI will lead with input from team members&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UMN will be exploring potential modeling approaches (broad scope)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;End result in Year 1 will be a list or tree of:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Modeling approaches with a short description&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Assumptions made at each step&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Implications of the assumption and approach&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A recommended approach that we will use for mAEWing2 and xAEWing3 based on those vehicles expected characteristics. Note: this tree will help guide designers through the process of picking a modeling approach. There are a lot of approaches and potential assumptions and no single approach will work best for every potential aircraft. We will simply be listing the potential methods, potential assumptions, and implications and pick what we think is the best approach for our aircraft.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is expected that this survey will not be completed in time for the mAEWing1 design, but will be used for the mAEWing2, xAEWing3, and N+3 modeling efforts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;maewing1-modeling-approach&quot;&gt;mAEWing1 Modeling Approach&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two approaches will be used for mAEWing1, the first is a CFD/CSD based approach and the second is a flight dynamics approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CFD / CSD
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;VT will create a FEM based on CAD, geometry, and material definitions for mAEWing1 supplied by UMN&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;CMSoft will create a CFD based on the Outer Mold Line (OML) of mAWing1 as defined by the CAD supplied by UMN&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;CMSoft will use the CFD and FEM to create a CFD/CSD model, which will be used to generate linear ROMs&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;STI will incorporate actuator models into the linear ROMs, which will then be used to design control laws for mAEWing1&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2 - 6 weeks out from having ROMs for mAEWing1&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flight dynamics
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Creates the NDOF model by adding a structural vibration solution and aeroelastic aero derivatives onto a rigid body dynamic model
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Advantages in providing insight into the flexible vehicle dynamics and being able to easily update the rigid body model based on aero and mass properties testing&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Will use rigid body aero from CMSoft’s CFD and FEM from VT; already have tools in place to extract required data from FEM&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maewing2-design&quot;&gt;mAEWing2 Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have preliminary CFD and FEM complete&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Need composite panel scaling for structure from UMN&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preliminary modal analysis and flutter speeds complete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mini-mutt-flight-testing&quot;&gt;mini MUTT Flight Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Analysis on Flight 17 complete&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looks like a higher gain on pitch damper could be helpful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planning on moving c.g. 0.25 inches forward; may provide increased pitch stability and will give insight into sensitivity of c.g. location&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planning on performing 3211 excitations on all surface pairs (only pitch and roll surfaces were tested last flight) to get a more complete aero data set&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planning on testing an auto land flight control law&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/02/19/status.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/02/19/status.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>status</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Status</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finding a day / time for mAEWing1 design review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;status-updates&quot;&gt;Status Updates&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;flight-testing&quot;&gt;Flight Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 excitations (3 pitch, 2 roll) captured during flight testing of the rigid vehicle on February 9th&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preliminary analysis of flight data indicates a 2.6 Hz short period frequency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May be able to get some parameters out to improve models, including improvement of the pitch damper design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investigating cause of a pitch oscillation in the second half of the test run&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Future testing
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Planning on using 3211 excitations targeted at 2 Hz symmetrically and asymmetrically on all surface pairs to enable SISO parameter estimation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Then will look into multisines, mutually orthogonal square waves, or pseudo random inputs to get data more efficiently&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Additional flight tests likely starting toward the end of February / early March&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maewing2-preliminary-design-and-manufacturing&quot;&gt;mAEWing2 Preliminary Design and Manufacturing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A side meeting will be set up to discuss some mAEWing2 configuration, material selection, and manufacturing options&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CMSoft performed preliminary CFD analysis of the mAEWing2 outer mold line (OML). 12 ft wingspan with an inviscid mesh, analysis performed at Mach 0.1 (34 m/s).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Preliminary lift and drag polar and CL vs alpha plots generated&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Work on generating a viscous mesh&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;mAEWing2 test condition Mach 0.115 (38 m/s)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ase-modeling&quot;&gt;ASE Modeling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Successful working meeting held at UMN February 5 and 6 with UMN, STI, VT, CMSoft, and Schmidt and Associates participating. Each participant presented their approach to modeling ASE systems and a simplified example problem was generated. Homework was to work through the simplified model and compare approaches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working through a simplified three body problem using several modeling approaches (Langrangian, mean axis, and force/torque balance equations) to find the benefits, drawbacks, and assumptions in each approach to find a good method for modeling ASE vehicles. Active email dialog and additional side meetings will be set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;meeting-presentations-on-githubhttpsgithubcompaawmeeting-updatestreemaster20150212&quot;&gt;Meeting Presentations on: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/PAAW/Meeting-Updates/tree/master/20150212&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/02/12/status.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/02/12/status.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>status</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strategic Meeting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Discussed MDAO approach for mAEWing2 and began discussing an alternative approach to modeling ASE vehicles for mAEWing1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;maewing2-mdao-approach&quot;&gt;mAEWing2 MDAO Approach&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Based on a 12 ft scale of X-56A geometry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UMN will send VT airspeed, altitude, and loading design points and ranges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will use VLM based aero for optimal shape determination
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;CMSoft to validate aero approach&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ase-modeling&quot;&gt;ASE Modeling&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meeting week of Feb 2 at the University of Minnesota to discuss ASE modeling approaches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;meeting-presentations-on-githubhttpsgithubcompaawmeeting-updatestreemaster20150122&quot;&gt;Meeting Presentations on: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/PAAW/Meeting-Updates/tree/master/20150122&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/strategic/2015/01/22/strategic.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/strategic/2015/01/22/strategic.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>strategic</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Status</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hold a strategic / tactical meeting next week on MDAO approach for mAEWing2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will also hold meetings on the modeling approach for aeroelastic vehicles, pertinent to mAEWing1, over the next couple of weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;status-updates&quot;&gt;Status Updates&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Need to schedule kickoff meeting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mAEWing1
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UMN received draft excitations from STI, inputs look good for integration into control laws&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Both spars built, design complete, and ordered wing core foam&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UMN completed additional testing on actuators, will have a finalized report uploaded to the conservancy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;NDOF modeling
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Should CMSoft create a full dynamic system model for mAEWing1?
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Right now focused on aerodynamic modeling for mAEWing2&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Could provide validation of our modeling process
                &lt;ul&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;CFD / FEM model &amp;lt;– currently we’re not pursuing this for mAWing1&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;DLM / VLM models&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Linear ROMs&lt;/li&gt;
                  &lt;li&gt;Control law designs&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ul&gt;
              &lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;We’re investigating modeling approaches and will keep asking this question during the next couple weeks&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;X-56
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;VT extracted mode shapes, developed beam model, and delivered to Dave S for modeling and control approach validation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Will clean up tools and paper for upload to the website and repositories&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/01/15/status.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/status/2015/01/15/status.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>status</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
